So let's go ahead and create a profit and loss statement for Ricard.
我们为 WeCart 建了一份损益表
Since we Ricard is a service company,
因为 WeCart 属于服务业的公司
I've included expenses that are typical service company and sales company would incur.
我包括了服务和销售行业公司通常会产生的几项支出
If this was a manufacturing company,
如果是制造业公司
some of the expenses that are missing in here would be
则有几项支出是这里没有的
the cost of the raw materials that you need to make your product.
例如制造产品所需的原材料成本
Let's get started. So, cost of goods sold would be the sum of these expenses.
那么 销货成本是这些支出的总和
The engineering costs for hosting the websites,
工程成本、网站的成本
for the charges for the payment system,
支付系统的费用、
packaging, and delivery costs.
包装和运输成本
So, I'll going ahead and added those up and that gives me the cost of goods sold.
把这些加起来得出销货成本
It's important to remember that your P and L statement and what goes into
很重要的一点是 损益表的各项
each line item changes by the type of business you are working with.
主要取决于你工作的公司业务类型
Again, if you're curious about it,
如果感兴趣
feel free to check out the links below. All right.
可以浏览下方的链接
Moving on, our gross profit is our revenue minus cost of goods sold,
接下来 毛利润是指收入减去总销货成本
and our selling general and administrative expenses are the salaries,
然后是销售及一般与行政支出 (英文简称 SGA)
legals fees, rent for office and utilities.
SGD 包括 薪水、律师费、办公室租金和水电费
This will be sum of these numbers.
这些数字求和
To get the total operating expenses,
另外 要计算总营业支出
I'm going to add in the recent development expenses as well.
也需要把近期的研发支出加进来
So, this will be sum of this and this SGAs.
所以是这一项加上 SGA 支出
So, to arrive at EBIT or earnings before interest and tax or operating profit or income,
要计算息税前利润 (EBIT) 或营业利润或收入
these are all synonymous for the same word,
（这三个词的意思基本是一样的）
you have to subtract the total operating expenses from the gross profit.
就是把毛利润减去营业总支出
Then, finally, to arrive at our net income or net profit,
最后 要计算净收入或净利润
you need to subtract from your EBIT or
要把息税前利润或营业利润或收入
operating profit the sum of your interest expenses and the income tax,
减去利息支出和所得税
and so we arrive at our net income.
得出了净收入
So, that's a profit and loss statement.
一份损益表做好了
You started with the total revenue,
首先是总收入
took out the expenses of building the products,
减去产品相关支出
which in the case of the Ricard here,
对于 WeCart 的例子
it's a SaaS company,
产品就是 “软件即服务” (SaaS)
I'm included the services cost as well.
所以也包括了服务成本
For a manufacturing company,
对于制造业公司
this would include the cost of raw materials,
我们还要包括原材料成本
got the gross profit.
这样就得出了毛利润
Then I took out the overhead expenses as a selling general and administrative expenses,
然后减去了间接费用 即销售、一般与行政支出
and then added the R and D expenses to get the total operating expenses,
接着加上了研发支出 得出营业总支出
then took out and used gross profit to take out
再把毛利润减去营业总支出
the total operating expenses and got my EBIT or operating profit.
得出息税前利润或营业利润
Then, finally, the interest expenses and income tax are taken out to get your net income.
最后 减去利息支出和所得税 得出净收入